Leah: Let's hear about the importance of
productive feedback in the scrum process.
Alex: I think that's such a key
element of the whole scrum process
is that that rapid feedback loop
that you're only kind of committing
to a small amount of work at a time.
And at the end of every sprint you are...
you're having a kind of sprint review,
you're demoing the product ideally to
the key stakeholders, ideally to the
end users or the customers, and you're
getting that feedback that rapid feedback
incorporating that back into the process
so that you can then work out what to
do differently for the next sprint and
how you can then evolve the product.
I would say it's important
throughout the whole process.
Quite specifically at the sprint reviews,
that's a great time for the team to kind
of demo the work that they've done for
the previous sprint and get that that
fast feedback from the stakeholders, from
the end users Also for the core scrum
team themselves at the retrospectives
to kind of review what went well, what
didn't go well, any kind of learnings.
And then again, incorporating
that into into the next sprint.
Just as part of that continuous
learning cycle, really.
Feedback can be given in a
variety of different ways.
And I think throughout the whole process
is it's important to get that feedback.
Again, going back to the key
sprint ceremonies, at the sprint
reviews, at the retrospectives.
Making sure you're giving kind of peer
feedback, peer review and feedback
throughout the process as well.
We do obviously hold daily scrums
every day, just to 15 minutes with
the core scrum team, for them to
talk about, you know, what they
did yesterday, what they're doing
today, any issues and blockers.
So, you know, hopefully it it's
a really open and honest kind of
communication and feedback for
the whole team on a daily basis.
And then also incorporating that feedback
from the stakeholders at the end of -- we
work in two week sprints -- and then
incorporating that then into, into what
we plan to do for the next two weeks.